<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>Equipment Deterioration</name>
	<author>LimeTreeSnake</author>
	<supportedVersions>
	<li>1.0</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	
	<description> 
Do you want things to deteriorate with time and use?
Vanilla Rimworld arbitrarily checks each day, each piece of apparel on each pawn, whether it should have it deteriorate by one point or not.
However, this is not done for weapons and other carried items. This mod rectifies this amongst adding other features.

Features:
-Option to remove vanilla deterioration thus with this mod it's entirely possible to remove all deterioration.
-Possibility to change chance of daily deterioration separately  for equipment, apparell and items in inventory carried/worn.
-Possibility to increase deterioration damage  separately for equipment, apparell and items carried/worn/used.
-Randomize damage done separately  to  equipment, apparell and items carried/worn/used.
-Deterioration rate depends on quality of product Awful->Legendary, entirely customizeable.
-Deterioration for NPC toggleable.
-Chance of deterioration whenever firing a ranged weapon.
-Chance of deterioration whenever bashing with weapons.
-Ranged Weapon jamming
-Ranged Weapon self damage chance increase per shot in a burst.
-All features Toggleable

-Special Thanks to-
Jecrell: cause he is great and his code helped me a lot.
Pardeike: cause of his work on Harmony.
XeoNovaDan: For his suggestion regarding quality.
LegendBraki: For his many suggestions.

-Links-
https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=46890.msg445480
https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1565674984
https://github.com/LimeTreeSnake/Equipment-Deterioration
https://discord.gg/3Xtr7e9 

-Compatibility-
Minigun2 uses logic that may cause some extreme deteriorations when used.
Adding/removing this mod mid-save may or may not have unforeseen consequences  but so does all mods.

Updates:
2019-08-10
	-Added Jamming logic.
	-Rearranged once again the UI.
	-Fixed an calculation issue where typecasting could have saved me a lot of trouble.
	-"Bullet Matters" works now as it should. lol.
	-Clarified info regarding Bullet Matters.
	-[XND]Proper Shotgun now works and so hopefully should every mod that has its own verbs.
	Hotfix:
		-Added a check to ensure that jamming only affects pawns with weapons.
		-Ammended the wild predators getting stuck.
2019-08-09
	-Changed firing logic. Now deals damage per burst instead of per bullet.
	-Added option "Bullet Matters" which increase percentage chance for deterioration depending on amount of bullets per burst.
	-Added Changeable Values per bullet.
	-Made sure World Pawns does not have their items deteriorate.
	-Option for users to exclude/include NPC deterioration.
	-Updated mod interface and made a few changes.
	-Code optimization
2019-08-08 
	-Added more deterioration options, 
	-option for quality affecting deterioration, 
	-bugfix: weapons detoriating upon use no longer cause a null exception. 
	-New mod settings interface.
Hotfix
	-Removed [XND]Proper Shotguns support as I have to learn more harmony. 
	-Fixed the percentage calculations that I had overlooked causing every shot to be deteriorating.
	-Items with 0 hp or less henceforth are indestructible. (Things like steel)
	-Inserted a check for items with no HP to not be calculated.
2018-11-25
	-resolved issue with turrets and other non-pawn things being calculated.
2018-11-19
	-Added functionality for deterioration of weapons upon use.
2018-11-16
	-Made the deteriorate value changeable through mod settings.

-License-
You may use this code as however you want. However, do notify me as I'd love to hear if people find use of my code! :)
	</description>
</ModMetaData>